Sandeep Kumar Singh

9205216121 | sandeep.bpgc@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Noida

SUMMARY

Proficient Software Engineer with experience in designing, developing, and implementing software applications. Utilize Java, JavaScript and Python to write scalable, secure code with a knack for problem-solving. Successfully optimized a software program resulting in a 60% efficiency increase.

EXPERIENCE

Freelancer Oct 2019 - Present

Senior Software Developer

Noida

Personal Finance Management with Cryptocurrency Integration | React, Node, MongoDB, Tailwind

- Enables users to track expenses, income, budgets, and financial goals, while also managing and monitoring cryptocurrency investments with real-time data from APIs like CoinGecko and CoinMarketCap
- Implemented JWT-based authentication and authorization
- Visualized data to show expenses and income

Real Time Collaboration Tool | Spring Boot, React, Web Socket, API

- Tool for real-time communication, enables multiple users to simultaneously edit documents, manage tasks on a Kanban board, and schedule events with calendar integration
- Implemented a Web Socket controller to handle real-time document editing messages
- Implemented a notification system to display real-time notifications to users

Restaurant Ordering and Delivery Management | Spring Boot, Java, React, MongoDB, API

- Local application to manage restaurant reservations and deliveries in a pre-defined area along with real time status
- Real time tracking of delivery associates

Developed over 50+ projects for clients as per their requirements

- Projects include tool development, API development and Full Stack applications
- Most used Languages and Frameworks include Spring, Java, React, SQL, MongoDB, API, Python, Node

Amazon Development Centre India Pvt. Ltd.

July 2015 - Aug 2016

SDET

 $New\ Delhi$

- \bullet Designed and implemented a REST API for test generation based on package parameters, resulting in a 60% increase in efficiency for the team
- Collaborated with the test teams across US and India to understand their requirements and tailor-made solutions to further optimise the dashboard and that increased their productivity by 35%.
- Developed a full stack application using Java, JSP, JavaSript and Hibernate to generate a customised report for tracking tickets for specific teams

Amazon Development Centre India Pvt. Ltd.

July 2014 - June 2015

 $Software\ Development\ Engineer\ Intern$

Bengaluru

• Developed a dashboard using Ruby on Rails to track the code changes going to production and reduced the team efforts from 72 hours to 18 hours

Moser Baer May 2012 - July 2012

Developer Intern

Greater Noida

• Developed an internal tool that automated routine weekly report for the Quality Control team increaseing the efficiency of team by 8%

EDUCATION

BITS Pilani, Goa

CGPA 8.78/10

B.E.(Hons.) Computer Science, M.Sc.(Hons.) Chemistry

2010 - 2015

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, Python, SQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTML/CSS, TypeScript

Frameworks: Spring, React, Node.js, NextJS, JUnit, Tailwind, Express

Developer Tools: Git, Docker, VS Code, Eclipse, LLD, HLD